Guide to the Montana Department of Environmental Quality, Director's Office records 1908-2002
Montana Historical Society
- Subject Files
  - Sulfur Dioxide, Discussion re: Ambient Air Quality (includes trans.), 1988 (Box-folder 67/4-5)
  - Air Rules, Wood Stoves Stacks, 1986 (Box-folder 67/6)
  - Air Rules, Wood Stoves Tax Credit, 1985 (Box-folder 67/7)
  - Air Rules, Wood Waste Burners, Petition to Revise, 1988 (Box-folder 67/8)
  - Anaconda Closure – Discussion with Labor Union leaders Of Anaconda, Butte, and Great Falls, 1980 (Box-folder 67/9)
  - Anaconda Aluminum, Quarterly Report, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 67/10)
  - ASARCO, Compliance (Lead), 1983 (Box-folder 67/11)
  - ASARCO, Copper-Silver Mine (Troy), 1983 (Box-folder 67/12)
  - ASARCO, Petition for Rule Change (SO2 emissions) (includes trans.), 1980 (Box-folder 67/13)
  - ASARCO, Variance Renewal (includes trans.), 1980 (Box-folder 67/14)
  - ASARCO, SO2 Study and Report on Study, 1980 (Box-folder 67/15)
  - (Gene) Anderson Tracts (subdivision) (includes trans. And exhibits), 1982 (Box-folder 67/16-17)
  - Angel’s Addition Subdivision (Stevensville) (includes trans.), 1979 (Box-folder 67/18)
  - Conoco, Air Quality Permit (includes trans., exhibits, and public comments), 1990 (Box-folder 67/19-24)
  - Amendment of ARM, Wood Waste Burners and Aluminum Plant Emissions, 1989 (Box-folder 68/1)
  - BHES, Meeting Items (includes Burlington Northern Open Burning Permit), 1989 March (Box-folder 68/2-4)
  - Conoco, Air Quality Permit (Court Papers, Correspondence Exhibits, Transcript, Testimony), 1989-1990 (Box-folder 68/5-13)
  - Open Burning Rule (includes Transcript), 1982 (Box-folder 68/14)
  - ASARCO, Rock Creek Project (Petition for Change In Ambient Water Quality, Public Comments), 1990 (Box-folder 69/1-3)
  - BHES, Billings/Laurel Air Quality Technical Committee (BAQTC) and Sulfur Dioxide Plan, 1989 (Box-folder 69/4-5)
  - BHES, Meeting Items, 1989 May -1990 June (Box-folder 69/6-12)
  - Noranda (Montanore), Non-degradation (EIS and Supplement to EIS), 1990 (Box-folder 69/13-14)
  - “ASARCO, Rock Creek Correspondence”, 1991 (Box-folder 70/2)
  - BHES, Meeting Items, 1991 February -1991 June (Box-folder 70/3-6)
  - Cabinet Resources Group, re: Permit requirements, 1990 (Box-folder 70/7-8)
  - “Comment in Response to Noranda Minerals Petition For Change in Quality of Ambient Waters”, 1990 (Box-folder 70/9)
  - Golden Sunlight Mines, Assessment of Water Quality Impacts, 1990 (Box-folder 70/10)
  - Hydrology Plan of Study, undated (Box-folder 70/11)
  - John’s IGA, Appeal of Permit (Commercial Waste Incinerator), 1991 (Box-folder 70/12)
  - “Noranda EIS File – Extension Correspondence”, 1990 (Box-folder 70/13)
  - State Implementation Plan (SIP), PM-10 Control Plan (Missoula, Kalispell), 1990 (Box-folder 70/14)
  - Stauffer Chemical Company, Variance, 1989 (Box-folder 70/15-16)
  - Stillwater Mining Company, Mine expansion and Discharge Of Pollutants, 1993 (Box-folder 70/17)
  - Sunbird Aviation, Gallatin Field Airport (Belgrade) (re: Installation of Underground Storage Tanks), 1990-1991 (Box-folder 70/18)
  - Underground Storage Tanks, Rules and Comments, 1989 (Box-folder 70/19)
  - “Department Circular re: Public Water Supply #1-3”, 1991 (Box-folder 71/2)
  - Missoula Air Pollution Control Program, Revisions, 1991 (Box-folder 71/3)
  - SHWB, Lewis and Clark County Class II Sanitary Landfill, 1991 (Box-folder 71/4)
  - Water Quality Bureau Circular #7, 1995 (Box-folder 71/5)
  - BHES, Meeting Items, 1992 June (Box-folder 71/6)
  - BER, ASARCO Request for Temporary Water Quality Standards in Upper Blackfoot River Mining Complex, 2000 (Box-folder 71/7)
  - BER, Blaine County Appeal of Notice of Violation (Cronk Gravel Pit, Pomeroy Gravel Pit), 2001-2002 (Box-folder 71/8)
  - BER, County Health Department Petition re: ARM 17.36.110, 1998 (Box-folder 71/9)
  - BER, Crown Butte Mines, Implementation Plan in Support Of Petition for Temporary Modification of Water Quality Standards, 1999 (Box-folder 71/10)
  - BER, EPA’s Approval of Non-Degradation Policy and Water Quality Standards, 2001 (Box-folder 71/11)
  - BER, Final Order re: Express Pipeline Certificate of Environmental Compatibility and Public Need, 2000 (Box-folder 71/12)
  - BER/BHES, General Correspondence, 1989-1999 (Box-folder 71/13)
  - BER, Gough, Shanahan, Johnson, and Waterman, Att. (Daisy Creek, Upper Stillwater, Fisher Creek, Upper Clark’s Fork, Cherry Lake/Cherry Creek), 1995, 1999 (Box-folder 71/14)
  - BER, Hydrogeochemical Study of Cow and Pony Creek Drainages, 1997 (Box-folder 71/15)
  - BER, Legislative Review (HB 521, 311), 2000 (Box-folder 71/16)
  - BER, Meeting Packets, Items, Minutes, 1995-1999 (Box-folder 71/17-19)
  - BER, Missoula County Air Pollution Control Board vs. BER, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 71/20)
  - BER, Missoula Air Quality Research Assistantship 1996-1997 (Box-folder 71/21)
  - BER, Notice of Proposed Amendment of Rules re: Water Quality, 1995 (Box-folder 71/22)
  - BER, Petition to Classify Gallatin River an Outstanding Resource Water (ORW), 2001-2002 (Box-folder 71/23)
  - BER, Pompey’s Pillar Historical Association vs. BHES/ United Harvest, 2001 (Box-folder 71/24-27)
  - BER, Proposed Amendment to Montana Water Quality Standards (re: Dioxin), 1999 (Box-folder 71/28)
  - BER, Testimony re: Revision of Lead SIP for East Helena, 1996 (Box-folder 71/29)
  - BER, Water Quality Permit Fees, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 71/30)
  - BER, ARCO Petition re: Site Specific Standards, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 72/1)
  - BER, Holnam Inc. Permit Appeal, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 72/2-8)
  - BER, Leading Edge Planes and Props BER, Logan Landfill, 1995 (Box-folder 72/9-10)
  - BER, Meeting Packet, 2001 July (Box-folder 72/11)
  - BER, “Miscellaneous Board Correspondence and Other”, 1990-2002 (Box-folder 72/12)
  - BER, “Smoke Management Fees” (trans.), 1995 (Box-folder 72/13)
  - BER, South Hills Water and Sewage District, 1995 (Box-folder 72/14)
  - BER, Water Quality Rules, Department of Justice Case # H2.99-103, 2001 (Box-folder 72/15)
  - BER, Woody’s Corporation (Notice of Violation re: Failure 1998-1999 To Monitor and Failure to Notify) (Box-folder 72/16)
  - BHES, East Helena SIP Hearing (court papers, transcripts), 1995 (Box-folder 72/17-18)
  - BHES, Amendment of Rules (Air Quality, Stack Heights, Permits, Open Burning), 1994-1995 (Box-folder 73/1)
  - BHES, Amendment of Rule re: Opacity Requirements at Kraft pulp mills, 1994 (Box-folder 73/2)
  - BHES, D+F Cleaners and Laundry (Bozeman), 1994 (Box-folder 73/3)
  - BHES, East Glacier Water and Sewer District, 1995 (Box-folder 73/4)
  - BHES, Hawthorne House, 1995 (Box-folder 73/5)
  - BHES, James Blankenship Underground Storage Tank Revoke, 1994 (Box-folder 73/6)
  - BHES, Leading Edge Planes and Props, 1994 (Box-folder 73/7)
  - BHES, Logan Landfill, 1995 (Box-folder 73/8)
  - BHES, Meeting Items, 1995 (Box-folder 73/9)
  - BHES, Mister “M” Disposal (Marvin Mintyala), 1995 (Box-folder 73/10)
  - BHES, Montana Power 401 Certification, 1994 (Box-folder 73/11)
  - BHES, Non-degradations Post-Hearing Comments, 1994 (Box-folder 73/12)
  - BHES, Nye’s Clothesline, 1995 (Box-folder 73/13)
  - BHES, Seeley Lake-Missoula County, 1995 (Box-folder 73/14)
  - BHES, Smoke Management Fee Rule (trans.), 1994 (Box-folder 73/15)
  - BHES, South Hills Waste and Sewer, 1995 (Box-folder 73/16)
  - BHES, Stone Container Corp. (trans.), 1994 (Box-folder 73/17-18)
  - BER, Meeting Packets, 1996 November - 1997 June (Box-folder 73/19-26)
  - BER, Meeting Packets, 1996 February- 1997 September (Box-folder 74/2-15)
  - BER, Contested Case, Montana Sulfur and Chemical Company (Court papers, exhibits, testimony), 1995-1996 (Box-folder 75/2-6)
  - BER, Meeting Packets, 1995 October–1997 October (Box-folder 75/7-13)
  - “Application of DEQ for the Revision of the Montana State Air Quality Control of SO2 Emissions in the Laurel/Billings Area” (Testimony, Studies and Models, Exhibits), 1995 December (Box-folder 76/3-8)
  - BER, Amendment of 17.30.716, Non Significant Activities Individual Sewage Systems, 1997 (Box-folder 76/9)
  - BER, Contested Case, Bozeman Landfill/Carter and Foster, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 76/10)
  - BER, Contested Case, Department of Corrections Deer Lodge Facility, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 76/11)
  - BER, Contested Case, Diamond City Mining Co. (James Collins), 1996-1997 (Box-folder 76/12)
  - BER, Contested Case, Donald Church – UST Installer/ Remover License, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 76/13)
  - BER, Contested Case, Express Pipeline Application to Construct Pipeline, 1996 (Box-folder 76/14)
  - BER, Contested Case, Montana Refining Company, 1998 (Box-folder 76/15)
  - BER, Water Quality Permit, Big Sky Water and Sewer, 1999 (Box-folder 76/16)
  - BER, Water Quality Violation, Department of Transportation, 1999 (Box-folder 76/17)
  - BER, Kraft Pulp Mill Opacity Hearing (trans.), 1998 (Box-folder 77/1)
  - BER, Meeting Packets, 1998 January - 1998 November (Box-folder 77/2-9)
  - BER, SO2 Control Strategies (Revision), 1996 (Box-folder 77/10)
  - “Express Crude Oil Pipeline, Draft Environmental Impact Statement”, 1995 (Box-folder 77/11)
  - Stone Container Corp., “re: Amendment of Rules Adding Human Health Risk Assessment to Pre-construction Permit Requirements for Incineration Facilities”, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 77/12-13)
  - BER, ARCO Site-specific Case re: Groundwater Rule (Application, Court filings/papers, opposition letters, Miscellany), 1998 (Box-folder 78/1-15)
  - Board of Health, ASARCO re: Ambient Air Standards For Sulfur Dioxides (trans.), 1971-1972 (Box-folder 79/1)
  - Board of Health, Air Pollution Public Hearing (re: SO2) (trans.), 1971 (Box-folder 79/2)
  - BER, Contested Case, Bozeman Longhorn Apartments (William Ladwig), 1998 (Box-folder 79/3)
  - BER, Contested Case, Glassco Lumber (Terry Claver), 1999 (Box-folder 79/4)
  - BER, Contested Case, “R Lazy M Enterprises D/B/A Creston Sand and Gravel”, 1998 (Box-folder 79/5)
  - BER, Contested Case, Troy Sand and Gravel (Michael and Sylvia Balbone, Scott and Teresa Curry), 1999 (Box-folder 79/6)
  - BER, Contested Case, Underground Storage Tank Liner/ Installer License (James Olsen), 1999 (Box-folder 79/7)
  - BER, Contested Case, Woody’s Corporation, 1999 (Box-folder 79/8)
  - Standards for Daisy Creek, Stillwater River, Fisher Creek, Upper Clark’s Fork (includes Meeting Packets, Requests To Question Witnesses, Public Comments, Sierra Club response, Water Quality Monitoring Data reports), 1995 (Box-folder 79/9-16)
  - BER, Meeting Packets, 1995 December (Box-folder 79/17-20)
  - Air Quality Permit, Williston Basin Interstate Pipeline Company (Legal documents, Testimony), 1995 (Box-folder 80/1-5)
  - BHES, Anaconda Company, Testimony re: Ambient Air Standards (Hannifan, Campbell, Laird, Cramer, Aufmuth, Treshow, Burton, Place), 1971 (Box-folder 80/6)
  - BHES, ASARCO (Request for hearing, re: Troy Unit), 1987 (Box-folder 80/7)
  - BHES, Burlington Northern Paradise Tie-treating Facility Variance, 1992 (Box-folder 80/8)
  - BHES, Cascade Subdivision Phase I (Madison County), 1992 (Box-folder 80/9)
  - BHES, Contract for Legal Services (C.W. Leaphart), 1981-1982 (Box-folder 80/10)
  - BHES, Hearing on Proposed Groundwater Monitoring Rules for Landfills, 1990 (Box-folder 80/11)
  - BHES, Lone Mountain Springs Inc (re: Hidden Village, Big Sky polluted water), 1992 (Box-folder 80/12)
  - BHES, Meetings Items, 1995 March-May (Box-folder 80/13-14)
  - BHES, Open Burning (“Christmas Tree Waste”), 1992 (Box-folder 80/15)
  - BHES, Pfizer Inc. Hearing re: Construction of Facility At Dillon, 1990 (Box-folder 80/16)
  - BHES, Public Comments and Petitions, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 80/17)
  - BHES, Request for Hearing (Craig Trueblood, ASARCO, Monad Auto Salvage), 1991 (Box-folder 80/18)
  - BHES, Rules Amendments and Adoptions, 1995 (Box-folder 80/19-20)
  - BHES, S.J. (Skip) Score vs. City of Helena/State of Montana (re: addition of fluoride to city water), 1992 (Box-folder 80/21)
  - BHES, Stauffer Chemical Report (fluoride, particulates), 1980 (Box-folder 80/22)
  - BHES, Stillwater Mining Company, Petition for Modification of Quality of Ambient Waters, 1991 (Box-folder 80/23)
  - BHES, Waste Management Partners of Bozeman (re: Solid Waste Management Act), 1990 (Box-folder 80/24)
  - BER, Meeting Packets, 1998 April - 1998 August (Box-folder 81/1-11)
  - BHES, Air Rules, ANA Petition (Statements, Miscellaneous correspondence, charts and graphs), 1971 (Box-folder 81/12-14)
  - BHES, “Petition to Modify State Standards…to Allow ASARCO’s East Helena Smelter and Anaconda Slag Treatment Plant to Continue Operation”, 1971 (Box-folder 81/15-16)
  - Ambient Air Submission, “Airborne Measurements of Stratosphere Ozone Intrusion into the Troposphere over the US”, 1980 (Box-folder 82/9)
  - Anaconda Company – Primary Metals, Anaconda Aluminum variance requests, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 82/10-11)
  - ASARCO, Application for Renewal of Variance, 1980 (Box-folder 82/12)
  - ASARCO variance, 1975, 1979 (Box-folder 82/13)
  - Board of Health (BH), Ambient Air Standards, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 82/14-16)
  - BH, Anaconda Company variance renewal, 1980 (Box-folder 82/17)
  - BH, Beaverhead County Sanitation – Landfill, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 82/18)
  - BH, Major Facility Siting Act (MFSA), 1982 (Box-folder 82/19)
  - BH, Montana Health Systems vs. BHES, 1978-1985 (Box-folder 82/20)
  - BH, Petition for Continuance of Hearings re: Stack Heights and Significant Deterioration Rule, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 82/21)
  - “Colstrip Sludge Pipeline”, 1999 (Box-folder 82/22)
  - Conoco, Exxon, and Farmer’s Union – Combined Motion For Review of Administrative Order re: Ambient Air, 1983-1990 (Box-folder 82/23)
  - Montana Power Company, Appeal of Ambient Air Quality Standards (Silver Bow), 1980-1983 (Box-folder 82/24)
  - Air Pollution Control Board, Advisory Council, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 83/24-25)
  - Air Pollution Material, 1970 (Box-folder 83/26)
  - BH, Meeting Items/Materials, 1971 March -1972 May (Box-folder 83/27-28)
  - BH, “Miscellaneous Documents”, 1987-1995 (Box-folder 83/29)
  - BHES, Sulfur Dioxide (SO2) State Implementation Plan (SIP), 1995 March (Box-folder 83/30)
  - BHES, SO2 SIP, 1995 April (Box-folder 83/31-32)
  - “Variance material”, 1970 (Box-folder 83/33)
  - BHES, Billings/Laurel SO2 Hearing, 1994 (Box-folder 84/12)
  - Crown Butte Mines, Petition to Amend ARM 16.8.608 to Reclassify Fisher, Daisy Creek, and Segments Of Stillwater and Clark’s Fork of Yellowstone River, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 84/13-16)
  - Crown Butte Mines, Petition to Amend ARM 16.8.608 to Reclassify Fisher, Daisy Creek, and Segments Of Stillwater and Clark’s Fork of Yellowstone River, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 85/1-3)
  - Air Rules, SIP (trans.), 1995 March, May (Box-folder 85/4)
  - Air Rules Hearing Materials, 1975 May (Box-folder 85/5)
  - Amendment of Rules (Sulfur in fuels, trans.), 1972 (Box-folder 85/6)
  - BHES, Meeting Items/Materials, 1995 May (Box-folder 85/7-12)
  - East Helena State Implementation Plan, 1995 (Box-folder 85/13)
  - Local Air Pollution Control Program, Libby – Lincoln County, 1994 (Box-folder 85/14)
  - SIP Revisions (trans.), 1982 (Box-folder 85/15)
  - Underground Storage Tanks Hearing, 1994 (Box-folder 85/16)
  - ASARCO, Sulfur Oxide variance and renewal, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 86/3-5)
  - ASARCO, Sulfur Oxide and Total Suspended Particulate (TSP), 1978 (Box-folder 86/6)
  - ASARCO, Air Pollution Variance (Discovery Documents, EIS, Depositions of Sweat, Varner, Lane, Wake, Anderson, Maughan, Holtz, Ripaldi, Gray, Keltz, Nelson), 1974 (Box-folder 86/7-9)
  - ASARCO, Lead Smelter and Zinc Fuming Plant (East Helena) (trans., court actions), 1974 (Box-folder 86/10-11)
  - ASARCO, “Miscellaneous Correspondence”, 1967-1980 (Box-folder 86/12)
  - ASARCO, Revision of SIP (East Helena) (trans.), 1975 (Box-folder 86/13)
  - ASARCO, Variance requests, 1974 (Box-folder 86/14)
  - ASARCO, Hearing Items/Materials, 1994 November-1995 January (Box-folder 86/15-19)
  - ASARCO, Meeting Items/Materials, 1995 March (Box-folder 86/20-22)
  - BHES, Montana Air Permit Fee Analysis, circa 1993 (Box-folder 87/1)
  - Board of Natural Resources and Conservation (BNRC), Meeting Packet (includes cassette tapes), 1986 May-1988 January (Box-folder 87/2-12)
  - ARCO-Warm Springs Ponds (Controlled Groundwater Area), 1995 (Box-folder 88/1)
  - BNRC, Blackfoot River (conservation easement), 1978 (Box-folder 88/2-3)
  - BNRC, Certificate of Service re: BPA kV Transmission Line, 1982 (Box-folder 88/4)
  - BNRC, Colstrip Sludge Pond/Ash Pond, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 88/5)
  - BNRC, Contested Case, Kalfell Ranch (Brief, Board Decision), 1992 (Box-folder 88/6)
  - BNRC, Genie Land and Livestock Company/Technical Committee (re: monitoring program), 1987 (Box-folder 88/7)
  - BNRC, Meeting Minutes and Materials, 1972-1989 January (Box-folder 88/8-13)
  - BNRC, North Dakota Atmospheric Resources Board Application for Weather Modification Permit (Petitions, Exhibits, Trans.), 1991-1992 (Box-folder 88/14-16)
  - BNRC, “Order of Board of Natural Resources Establishing Water Reservations”, 1978 (Box-folder 88/17)
  - BNRC, Oral Arguments re: Missouri River Reservations, 1992 (Box-folder 88/18)
  - BNRC, “Slurry Spill” (Colstrip), undated (Box-folder 88/19)
  - BNRC, Sun River Floodplain (Great Falls) (Final Order), 1984 (Box-folder 88/20)
  - BNRC, “Application of Montana Power…for Proposed Colstrip Units 3 and 4 (Court filings, transcript, etc.), 1975-1985 (Box-folder 89/9-16)
  - BNRC, Council on Management Recommendations, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 89/17)
  - BNRC, Laurel to Bridger 100 kV Transmission Line (cassette tapes), 1986 (Box-folder 89/18)
  - BNRC, “A Final Report and Request for Federal Assistance, A Study of the Feasibility of Tribal Assumption of 404 Activities on the Flathead Reservation” (Volumes I-IV), 1990 (Box-folder 90/1-2)
  - BNRC, “Application for Treatment as a State Under Section 303 – Water Quality Standard of the Clean Water Act (Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribes) (Public Comments, Petitions, Exhibits), 1992 (Box-folder 90/3-7)
  - BNRC, Miscellaneous (Correspondence, etc.), 1989-1992 (Box-folder 90/8)
  - BNRC, “Tribal Water Quality Ordinance 89B”, 1991 (Box-folder 90/9)
  - BNRC, Water Reservations (Court papers, filings), 1977-1978 (Box-folder 90/10)